onlineprinters.com 2018-09-05

# Privacy Policy | Onlineprinters

Our Privacy Policy describes the types of information we collect from you when you visit and/or use our Site, Onlineprinters.com, and explains what we do with that information. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, including the use of your personally identifiable information in any manner described here, you may be prohibited from using much of our websites and services (the “Services”), including revocation of your account. Onlineprinters may update this Privacy Policy from time-to-time in our sole discretion.  In such case, Onlineprinters will attempt to provide you with notice to the email address on file for your account, no less than 30 days prior to any such update.  It is your responsibility to check your email for updates, and to review the Privacy Policy for any changes.  You agree that each time that you use the Site and Services and you are bound by any such changes. Use of the Site and Services by you following us emailing you or posting a new privacy policy on our Site constitutes your acceptance of the Privacy Policy as modified.

You can visit our websites without providing any personal data. Each time you call a website, the web server just automatically saves a so-called server log file, which contains, for example, the name of the requested file, your IP address, date and time of the call, the amount of transmitted data, and the requesting provider (access data) and documents the call.  

These access data are analysed for the purpose of ensuring failure-free operation of the website and improving our offer. This serves to safeguard our – within the scope of a weighing of interests – overriding legitimate interests in a correct presentation of our offer pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 s. 1 lit. f GDPR.  

### 1\. Use of Personal Information   

#### What information do we collect?

  * Registration information - When you sign up for the Site, we ask for your personal information. In some cases, we may also ask you to send us additional information or to answer additional questions to help verify your information.
  * Information obtained from third parties - We may obtain information about you from third parties to verify the information you provide. We also may obtain information from third parties in connection with providing the Services to you.
  * Submission and Order information – When you submit information through the website or via email, we may store that information and also collect and store metadata about that information. We do not screen for personally identifying information; to the extent you have included any such information in your submissions and orders, it will be stored and disclosed in the course of our general use of such information.
  * Information about your use of the Services - We may collect information about your interaction with the service to help validate your identity or detect potentially fraudulent conduct.
  * User-provided contact information –Onlineprinters may track and/or gather emails of visitors that contact and/or communicate with Onlineprinters.
  * Cookies - When you access the Onlineprinters.com web page, we may send one or more cookies (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers’ systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information).
  * User communications - When you send an email or other communication to us.
  * Links - We may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed.

#### What do we use your information for?

  * To process your orders and transactions – Your information will be collective if submitted by you when you place an order to perform and process your order.
  * To personalize your experience – Your information helps us better respond to and tailor our Site and Services to your individual needs, including to serve user-specific advertisements based on your use of our Site or web history.
  * To improve our Site – we continually update and improve our website and Services based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
  * To improve customer service
  * To administer promotions, surveys or other Site features
  * To send you newsletters and/or periodic emails – the email address you provide for registration purposes may be used to send you information about this website, in addition to occasional news, updates, related product or service information (including, but not limited to sharing such non-specific information with third parties), etc. Users may opt in to receive promotional communications from Onlineprinters or our third-party partners. Users may opt out of receiving emails from Onlineprinters by clicking the corresponding "unsubscribe" link found in each and every communication sent from Onlineprinters.
  * We will not disclose or sell personally identifiable data to third parties, except as necessary to provide the services. If you do not want your non-personally identifying data shared, you may write to us at E-Mail: dataprotection(at)onlineprinters.com.  Alternatively, you may opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for personalized experiences by visiting <http://optout.aboutads.info/>. You understand and agree that any decision you make to withhold any information from Onlineprinters may prevent Onlineprinters from being able to fulfill your request, your order and/or impair your ability to utilize all functionality of the Site.

#### How do we protect your information?

  * The security of your personal information is important to us. Onlineprinters has implemented various security features to help prevent any unauthorized release of personal information. Our features include technical and physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data.
  * When you enter sensitive information (such as address and payment information) on our registration forms or Site, we encrypt that information using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption when you authenticate (i.e., log into one of our Services), which helps prevent unauthorized access to your login credentials. We limit access to personal information to employees or contractors who need that access to perform their jobs; and provide company-wide training on privacy and data security.
  * Be advised that while Lineprinter has endeavored to make a secure reliable Site for its users, the privacy and confidentiality of communications transmitted to/from Onlineprinters.com via this Site or through email cannot be guaranteed. As such, Onlineprinters is not held responsible for the security of any data transmitted via the Internet to/from our website.
  * The security of your account also depends on keeping your account password confidential and you should not share your account name or password with anyone. If you do share your account information with a third party, they will have access to your account and your personal information. 

### 2\. Accessing and Editing Your Personal Information  

To the extent that such personal information is stored in our databases, we will respond to your changes as soon as reasonably possible. Please note that although you may terminate your account or access to our Services, your personal information may remain stored indefinitely in our backup and archival records. While your personal information is protected as outlined above, we reserve the right to use, transfer, sell, and share aggregated, anonymous data about our users as a group for any business purpose, such as analyzing usage trends and seeking compatible advertisers and partners.

### 3\. Third party links  

At our discretion, we will be including or offer third party products or services on our Site. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our Site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### 4\. Age Restrictions  

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), as we do not collect any information from anyone under 18 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 18 years old or older.  If you are under the age of 18, please do not submit any personal information through the Site. 

### 5\. Changes to this policy  

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will post any Policy changes on this page. Each version of this Policy will be identified by its effective date.

If you have any questions about this Policy, please feel free to contact us through the Site or write to us at    

Andreas Neuer  
Data Protection Officer  
E-Mail: [dataprotection(at)onlineprinters.com](mailto:dataprotection@onlineprinters.com)

April 01, 2018

Our Privacy Policy information is available here as a [downloadable PDF-file](https://d2slpf6wny259j.cloudfront.net/_Resources/PdfPage/9bb952d38db47d8ff02c44750ed61dcefefa73da/Privacy_Policy.pdf "Opens external link in new window").
